Rajdeep Rathore

• Kheri, UP **R** Portfolio **(7)** Github **in** LinkedIn

Profile

Diligent and dedicated individual with more than one year of experience in web development domain. Seeking opportunities as full stack developer in a progressive organization. I'm self-motivated, team player with strong problem solving skills, ready to learn ins & outs of industry and provide ample value to employer.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, node.js, Express, MongoDB, Vite.js, Bootstrap, REST APIs, Next.js, MySQL

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Mewar University 2018 | Chittorgarh, Rajasthan Electrical Engineering | 8.81 CGPA

Intermediate, Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya 2014 | Mitauli Kheri, U.P PCM with Comp. Science | 86.60%

Certificates

Full Stack Developer Trainee

Skill Academy by Testbook | 2022-23

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp from **Udemy, 2021**

Certificate Number: UC-ec095765-266c-4b05-9788-81a747d92ec6

Achievements

Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE), Qualified - 2019, 2020, 2021

Industrial Proficiency and Aptitude Test (CII-iPATE) Qualified - 2020

Languages Known

English, Hindi, Punjabi, Odiya

Hobbies

Reading novels, Sketch making

Professional Experience

Software Developer, *Data-Vector Tech Pvt Ltd* □ 05/2023 - present

- Developed responsive and user-friendly web applications ensuring cross browser compatibility.
- Implemented modern front-end framework React.js and it's tools **Vite.js** & **Typescript** to create dynamic user interfaces.
- Integrated APIs to enhance application functionalities for efficient data retrieval and manipulation.
- Led frontend of projects: Remote Device Management System, Ticket Management System and DMS Portfolio

Full Stack Developer Trainee, *Skill Academy* 01/2022 - 01/2023

- Successfully completed a full-stack development career program mastering essential web development tools & technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js & MongoDB.
- Learned version control system git, github & gitlab
- Developed full-stack application showcasing proficiency in both front-end and back-end technologies

Sr. Business Analyst, Tesca Technologies Pvt. Ltd. □ 08/2020 - 11/2021

- Provided consultation to international buyers by understanding their queries & generating RFQs.
- Led a team of 10+ members and delivered results.
- Supplier Performance & cost reduction management

Graduate Engineer Trainee, Omega Electronics Pvt. Ltd. 05/2019 - 04/2020

- Undertook Research & Development and introduced several new products.
- Handled quality assurance

Projects

Remote Device Management System Frontend Tech: React.js, Vite.js, React Suite, emotion/react & Bootstrap

Ticket Management System

Frontend Tech: React.js, Vite.js, Typescript, Bootstrap and emotion/react

Bookskart, Dummy e-commerce website for finding and purchasing books online

• Technologies: React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Auth0.

Hotel Booking Site, *Interactive platform for finding and* booking rooms like Airbnb

• Technologies: Express, JWT Auth, JS, Mongoose, HTML,CSS, Bootstrap.